A Guide to Recordings of University of Virginia Events, 1975-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Recordings of University of Virginia Events 1975-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-4/2/9.961
This collection consists of 289 recordings (24 cassette tapes, 166 5-inch audio reels and 99 7-inch audio reels.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Archival transfer fromUniversity of Virginia Information Services, 1996 August 13.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains recordings of speeches and interviews by or with Bella Abzug, Richard A. Beaumont, Ray Bice, James Boren, George Bowles, Robert Caneveri, Irby Cauthen, John Chafee, the Dalai Lama, Ernest Ern, Gerald Ford, Mills Godwin, Sheldon Hackney, Bruce P. Hayden, Frank, Hereford, Chaim Herzog, Luther Hodges, A. E. Dick Howard, Hugh P. Kelly, Bowie Kuhn, Bert Lance, Dumas Malone, Frederick Nichols, Merrill Peterson, J. Kenneth Robinson, B.F.D. Runk, Hugh Scott, Thomas Storrs, Kwame Ture, and Stansfield Turner.
Topics on the tapes include acid rain, adolescent suicide, career planning, civil rights and Martin Luther King, Jr., Halley's comet, mainstreaming handicapped children, Iran, nuclear energy, the Panama Canal Treaty, senior citizen fitness, Virginia's weather and climate.
Many topics pertain to the University of Virginia including athletics, capital campaign, convocation (1981), finals (1980), founders day, the Good Old Song, the honor system, intramural and recreational sports, Thomas Jefferson, and rare books.
Contents List
- Unknown [rough cut?] (Box 1)
  0014
- Unknown (Box 1)
  0015
- Campaign Slide Show, rough edit (Box 1)
  0016
- Battle April 9, 1982, The Public Eye #5 (Box 1)
  0017
- Walter Nadlington and Andrew Wright "Violence in the family, spouse abuse," Medical Center House, 22 February 1978 (Box 1)
  0018
- N. Graham Claytor, Jr., Secretary of the Navy Panama Canal Forum (Box 1)
  0019
- Bowie Kuhn (Box 1)
  Press briefing at law school, 3 April 1978 0020
- Chaim Herzog, Israeli ambassador to the United Nations (Box 1)
  Newcomb Hall Ballroom, 18 April 1978 0021
- Anthony Troy, Attorney General of Virginia Bond Referendum, 22 August 1977 (Box 1)
  0022
- Pierre Rinfret on the M.E. question from Sponsor's Day (Box 2)
  Darden School 30 September 1977 0023
- Panama Canal Symposium with John Chafee (pro) and William T. Mott (con) Old Cabell Hall Auditorium, 10 February 1978 (Box 2)
  0024
- Hugh Scott, Fall Convocation Comments on the Panama Canal treaty, 21 October 1977 (Box 2)
  0025
- Dumas Malone Ceremony I (Box 2)
  0026a
- Dumas Malone Ceremony II (Box 2)
  0026b
- Comet watch I, 1 and 2 of 7 (Box 2)
  0027a
- Comet watch II, 5 of 7 (Box 2)
  0027b
- Comet watch III, 7 of 7 (Box 2)
  0027c
- Comet watch IV, 6 of 7 (Box 2)
  0027d
- Adolescent suicide; Fitness for senior citizens, August 19-25 (Box 2)
  0028a
- Adolescent suicide; Fitness for senior citizens, August 19-25 (Box 2)
  0028b
- Continuing education, August 26-September 1 (Box 2)
  0029a
- Continuing education, August 26-September 1 (Box 2)
  0029b
- Finding a job, July 15-21 (Box 2)
  0030
- Nuclear energy, an interview with Professor Thomas Williamson, the chairman of the department of nuclear engineering at University of Virginia, July 22-28 (Box 3)
  0031
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, August 5-11 (Box 3)
  0032a
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, August 5-11 (Box 3)
  0032b
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, part II, August 12-18 (Box 3)
  0032c
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, part II, August 12-18 (Box 3)
  0032d
- Interview with Richard Neel, the editor-in-chief of the Cavalier Daily student newspaper on the Grounds, July 8-14 (Box 3)
  0033
- Commencement address by Supreme Court Justice William Rehnquist, June 3-9 (Box 3)
  0034
- Rare books at University of Virginia, July 29-August 4 (Box 3)
  0035a
- Rare books at University of Virginia, July 29-August 4 (Box 3)
  0035b
- Rare books at University of Virginia, July 29-August 4 (Box 3)
  0035c
- Rare books at University of Virginia, July 29-August 4 (Box 3)
  0035d
- Coleman, 21 August 1978 (Box 3)
  0036
- John Colley Darden (Box 3)
  0037
- Dick Howard Law (Box 3)
  0038
- Acid Rain (Box 4)
  0039
- Five three-minute programs (Box 4)
  I. Sort of in honor of Valentine's Day, a sweetheart of a cardiologist looks at hearts from an unsentimental angle. II. Tony Sanchez of Laredo used to pick up coal on the railroad tracks to heat his hovel. Finally he's warm and rich because he has gas. III. How do you make the most of your evanescent stardom or notoriety? You try to get Mark McCormack to take you on as a client. IV. He wouldn't say so because he's too young to retire, but Tom Casey, a disaster expert, ranks politicians among the major hazards. V. How about whimsical paintings to liven up a wall or storefront? Greg Brown of Palo Alto has proved they're a good idea. [from cue sheet in case] Week of February 13. 0040
- University of Virginia Reider interviews [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0041
- Willie Cowe student interviews [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0042
- Interviews with Ken Garrett, Robert Gallanzer, Pat McGuire, Ann Mackay (Box 4)
  0043
- Chimes at noon (Box 4)
  0044
- Interviews Bradford Robertson, Allan Fitzpatrick (Box 4)
  0045
- Interviews with Jim Pardo, Frank Warren (Box 4)
  0046
- Gilbert Sullivan (Box 4)
  0047
- Landon Hall, part I, student interview [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0048a
- Landon Hall, part II, student interview [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0048b
- Allen Fitzpatrick, part I, University of Virginia-student interview [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0049a
- Allen Fitzpatrick, part II, Ken Garrett - part I, University of Virginia - student [1 page of notes in case] (Box 4)
  0049b
- University of Virginia student Ken Garrett - part II (Box 4)
  0050
- 26-Feb-75 (Box 5)
  Dumas Malone, Sync. Footage for 68 feet, Wild sound interview, continues University of Virginia Reider [1 page of notes in case] 0051
- Dean Irby Cauthen (Box 5)
  0052
- David Weiss (Box 5)
  0053
- Robert Caneveri (Box 5)
  0054
- B. F. D. Runk (Box 5)
  0055
- Ernest Ern (Box 5)
  0056
- Dumas Malone, part I (Box 5)
  0057a
- Dumas Malone, part II (Box 5)
  0057b
- Radio Television Center Tape (Box 5)
  0058
- Radio Television Center Tape (Box 5)
  0059
- Radio Television Center Tape (Box 5)
  0060
- Radio Television Center Tape (Box 5)
  0061
- Radio Television Center Tape (Box 5)
  0062
- Unknown (Box 5)
  0063a
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063b
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063c
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063d
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063e
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063f
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063g
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063h
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063i
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063j
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063k
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063l
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063m
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063n
- Unknown (Box 6)
  0063o
- Unknown (Box 7)
  0063p
- Unknown (Box 7)
  0063q
- Unknown (Box 7)
  0063r
- Unknown (Box 7)
  0063s
- Unknown (Box 7)
  0063t
- Public service box (Box 7)
  0064
- Public service box (Box 7)
  0065
- Professor Day classroom, 17 October 1975 (Box 7)
  0066
- Beanning Hoffman and David Weisstub Medical Center Hr. on "Deprogramming the Converted" 4 January 1978 (Box 7)
  0067
- Julia Martin and William Serow Comments on TMI population study, 1970-1975, 9 January 1978 (Box 7)
  0068
- Stanisfield Turner, CIA Director Chemistry Auditorium, 2 December 1977 (Box 7)
  0069
- James Boren, President, International Association of Professional Bureaucrats Darden School Business Forum, 13 December 1977 (Box 7)
  0070
- Dr. Milton Edgarton Transsexual program, Medical Center Hour, 7 September 1977 (Box 7)
  0071
- Gov. Mills E. Godwin, Jr. Student Legal Forum The 1977 Bond Referendum, 6 October 1977 (Box 7)
  0072
- Terrorism and the Media (Box 8)
  Robert Rabe, D.C. Metropolitan Police; Neil Hickey, T.V. Guide. John Bassett Moore Symposium, Law School, Rm. 119 14 October 1977 0073
- Abdel Meguid, Egyptian Ambassador to U.N. Newcomb Hall Ballroom, 4 April 1978 (Box 8)
  0074
- Michael Bednar, University of Virginia Associate Professor of Architecture interview with L.R. Barnes for [VCH?] Architecture School, 9 November 1977 Subject: playground for handicapped children (Box 8)
  0075
- Bella Abzug Gilmer Auditorium 18 April 1978 Student's Legal Forum/Virginia Law Women (Box 8)
  0076
- Children and Medical Care June 10-16 (Box 8)
  0077
- Mainstreaming handicapped children August 5-11 (Box 8)
  0078a
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, part II August 12-18 (Box 8)
  0078b
- Mainstreaming handicapped children August 5-11 (Box 8)
  0079a
- Mainstreaming handicapped children, part II August 12-18 (Box 8)
  0079b
- Continuing education August 26-September 1 (Box 8)
  0080
- Adolescent suicide; fitness for senior citizens August 19-25 (Box 8)
  0081a
- Adolescent suicide; fitness for senior citizens August 19-25 (Box 8)
  0081b
- Nuclear energy, an interview with Professor Thomas Williamson, the chairman of the department of nuclear engineering at University of Virginia July 22-29 (Box 8)
  0082
- Rare books collections at University of Virginia July 29-August 4 (Box 8)
  0083
- Career planning July 1-7 (Box 9)
  0084
- Virginia's weather and climate, a discussion with Bruce Hayden, professor at the University and climatologist for Virginia April 8-14 (Box 9)
  0085
- News of the University of Virginia (Box 9)
  0086
- News of the University of Virginia/Weiss [1 page of notes in case] (Box 9)
  0087
- 3 versions 90" mixed master and 30" spot (Box 9)
  0088
- Robinson spot (Box 9)
  0089a
- Rep Robinson spot (Box 9)
  0089b
- Honor system [1 page of notes and one receipt in case] (Box 9)
  0090
- The Glee Club: The Good Old Song (Box 9)
  0091
- Unedited Hereford (Box 9)
  0092
- Council I (Box 9)
  0093a
- Council II (Box 9)
  0093b
- Council III (Box 9)
  0093c
- Hugh Kelly, physics [1 page of notes in case] (Box 9)
  0094
- Kinard (Box 10)
  0095
- Noble (Box 10)
  0096
- Commentary? George Bowles (Box 10)
  0097
- Kellogg's Slide Tape (Box 10)
  0098
- F[rederic?] Seitz Fall Commencement (Box 10)
  0099
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100a
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100b
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100c
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100d
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100e
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100f
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100g
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100h
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 10)
  0100i
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 11)
  0100j
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 11)
  0100k
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 11)
  0100l
- Radio and Television unknown (Box 11)
  0100m
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101a
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101b
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101c
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101d
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101e
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101f
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101g
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101h
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101i
- Unknown (Box 11)
  0101j
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101k
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101l
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101m
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101n
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101o
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101p
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101q
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101r
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101s
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101t
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101u
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101v
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101w
- Unknown (Box 12)
  0101x
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0101y
- University of Virginia Reider Roll 4 (Box 13)
  0102
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103a
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103b
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103c
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103d
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103e
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103f
- Unknown (Box 13)
  0103g
- Sans music Art II (Box 13)
  0104
- Slide show master audio (Box 13)
  0105
- Slide show master voice (Box 13)
  0106
- NUVA weeks 8/6 and 8/13 (Box 13)
  0107
- Kenneth Copeland Commercial Time (Box 13)
  0108
- Unknown (Box 14)
  0109
- Hugh Kelly, Nancy Lyons (Box 14)
  0110
- John Coney (Box 14)
  0111
- Robertson (Box 14)
  0112
- Campaign Slide Show IV and V for April 23 showing (Box 14)
  0113
- Rough cut 25 April 1983, sound released, (retaped) Good Old Song in unison w/ edit (Box 14)
  0114
- Hundley Art (Cops and Mores) (Box 14)
  0115
- Bert Lance (Box 14)
  0116
- University of Virginia Slide Show 21 March 1984 (Box 14)
  0117
- Jefferson and the University Frederick Nichols 26 November 1973 (Box 14)
  0118
- Sheldon Hackney, "Southern Business: The past as prologue" 24 September 1979, 1 of 3 (Box 14)
  0119a
- Sheldon Hackney, "Southern Business: The past as prologue" 24 September 1979, 2 of 3 (Box 14)
  0119b
- Sheldon Hackney, "Southern Business: The past as prologue" 24 September 1979, 3 of 3 (Box 14)
  0119c
- President Gerald R. Ford University Hall 11 October 1979, 1 of 2 (Box 14)
  0120a
- President Gerald R. Ford Press Conference, University of Virginia 11 October 1979, 2 of 2 (Box 15)
  0120b
- Southern Society: The probable future Samuel D. Cook/John S. Reed, Jr. University of Virginia 1 October 1979 [from container], 2 of 2 [tape labeled "Dubois Steele] (Box 15)
  0121
- News of the University of Virginia John Lafley, University of Virginia intramural and recreational sports August 6-12, 1978 and August 13-19, 1978 (Box 15)
  0122
- The Southern Economy Thomas I. Storrs, 22 October 1979, 2 of 2 (Box 15)
  0123
- Raymond Bice Speech 1980 (Box 15)
  0124
- Forum on Athletics (Hereford, Hunt, Corrigan) I (Box 15)
  0125
- Luther D. Hodges, Jr. 14 April 1980, 2 of 3 (Box 15)
  0126
- Rough cut, slide show March 1983 "Good Old Song" in unison (Box 15)
  0127
- 1981 Fall Convocation (Box 15)
  0128
- Richard A. Beaumont 24 March 1980 (Box 15)
  0129a
- Richard A. Beaumont 24 March 1980 (Box 15)
  0129b
- Richard A. Beaumont 24 March 1980 (Box 15)
  0129c
- Iran forum 28 January 1980 (Box 15)
  0130a
- Iran forum 28 January 1980 (Box 15)
  0130b
- Iran forum 28 January 1980 (Box 16)
  0130c
- Iran forum 28 January 1980 (Box 16)
  0130d
- Stories from the market place: consumer news for students: public affairs series for young people [1 page of notes in case] (Box 16)
  0131
- Master 12 June 1982 (Box 16)
  0132
- Kwame Toure (Stokely Carmichael) 30 January 1980, reel 3 (Box 16)
  0133a
- Kwame Toure (Stokely Carmichael) 30 January 1980, reel 2 (Box 16)
  0133b
- Kwame Toure (Stokely Carmichael) 30 January 1980, reel 1 (Box 16)
  0133c
- 60" TV Script Edited 209 August 1984 Robert Waller, narrator (Box 16)
  0134
- Luther D. Hodges, Jr. 14 April 1980, 3 of 3 (Box 16)
  0135
- Mixed Master 28 June 1984 (Box 16)
  0136a
- Master 28 June 1984 (Box 16)
  0136b
- University of Virginia Campaign Audio Track sans music (Actualities complete) Voice track - narration, campaign fund slide show (Box 16)
  01037
- Half-time show, mixed 12 January 1984 Basketball spot soundtrack (Box 16)
  0138
- Iran press conference 28 January 1980, 1 of 2 (Box 16)
  0139
- Forum on Athletics (Hereford, Hunt, Corrigan) II (Box 17)
  0140
- Southern Society: The probable future Samuel Cook/John S. Reed, Jr. 1 October 1979 [tape labeled Dubois Steele], 1 of 2 (Box 17)
  0141
- Bowser/Zelnick [on spine] [label on box reads: News of the University of Virginia John Lafley, University of Virginia intramural and recreational sports 6-12 August 1978, 13-19 August 1978] (Box 17)
  0142
- Colgate Darden convocation Cabell Hall Auditorium, 9 October 1981 (Box 17)
  0143
- Final exercises, 18 May 1980 Speaker: Charles L. Brown, chairman of the American telephone and telegraph company (Box 17)
  0144
- 1981 Fall convocation 23 October 1981 (Box 17)
  0145
- Jefferson in Europe Frederick D. Nichols 19 November 1973 (Box 17)
  0146
- Luther D. Hodges, Jr. 14 April 1980, 1 of 3 (Box 17)
  0147
- Jefferson and the Presidency Dumas Malone 5 November 1973 (Box 17)
  0148
- Jefferson, the Enlightenment and the Revolution Merrill D. Peterson, 1 of 2 (Box 17)
  0149a
- Jefferson, the Enlightenment and the Revolution Merrill D. Peterson, 2 of 2 (Box 17)
  0149b
- Civil Rights: Dead with the King Greene II original (Box 17)
  0150
- The Southern Economy Thomas Storrs 22 October 1979, 1 of 2 (Box 17)
  0151
- Inauguration prologue (Box 17)
  0152a
- Inauguration prologue (Box 18)
  0152b
- Founder's Day 1979 (Box 18)
  0153
- News of the University of Virginia 23-29 July 1978 Dr. Robert Brown, physical fitness and depression 30 July-5 August 1978 Annette Gibbs and Thomas Sellars New student profile and Blue Ridge Hospital Division (Box 18)
  0154
- Capital campaign announcement The Rotunda 7 December 1981 (Box 18)
  0155
- Public Eye #908 From eve to the era Slide show rough cut II (Box 18)
  0156
- for Bill, J.S. Bach [note on case:Bach - Gavotte I with Percussion/for International Services University of Virginia? ] (Box 18)
  0157
- Soundtrack for engineering research 60" 90" 60" in order with music by Donald MacInnis (Box 18)
  0158
- President Gerald R. Ford University Hall 11 October 1979, 2 of 2 (Box 18)
  0159
- Foxworth (Box 18)
  0160
- Rough Cut IV (Box 18)
  0161
- Art Research (Box 18)
  0162
- Carpenter [on reel: News of the University of Virginia weeks of 7/23 and 7/30] (Box 18)
  0163
- Art '82 (Box 18)
  0164
- His Holiness the Dalai Lama, September 13, 1979 Jeffrey Hopkins, translator (Box 18)
  0165
- Rough cut June 1982 (Box 19)
  0166
- E. Blaine Liner 31 March 1980, 1 of 3 (Box 19)
  0167a
- E. Blaine Liner 31 March 1980, 2 of 3 (Box 19)
  0167b
- E. Blaine Liner 31 March 1980, 3 of 3 (Box 19)
  0167c
- Rough cut 1983 [spine labeled 1982, case and disc labeled 1983] (Box 19)
  0168
- Basketball spot soundtrack (Box 19)
  0169
- University of Virginia Campaign Rough cut with music (Box 19)
  0170
- New rough cut December 1982 (Box 19)
  0171
- President Hereford 24 May 1984 Edited (Box 19)
  0172
- Iran Press Conference 28 January 1980, 2 of 2 (Box 19)
  0173
- University of Virginia Campaign music track (Box 19)
  0174
- Ownby World Health Org. (Box 19)
  0175
- Kwame Ture (Stokely Carmichael) Press conference 30 January 1980 (Box 19)
  0176
- 60" TV Scripts and Original Robert Walker, narrator (Box 19)
  0177
- Art: Revised ST Jan. 83 (Box 20)
  0178
- Ingham as Jefferson Art (second recording) (Box 20)
  0179
- Hereford Iia (Box 20)
  0180
- Good Old Song (Box 20)
  0181
- Iran Forum 28 January 1980, 3 of 5 (Box 20)
  0182
- Master tape for Halley's Comet (comet watch), 3 and 4 of 7 (Box 20)
  0183